[Autogenerated] In this clip, we're going
to discuss payload detection rule options,
specifically focusing on the content
option and a few of its associated
features. Content allows us to investigate
the payload and detect specific strings,
bits and patterns that indicate a
potential attack. Let's look at an example
situation where this would be valuable as
we discussed in the last module, there
will be situations where you could write a
simple rule, and it would successfully
detect an attacker's traffic. However, if
you simply blocked a destination by port
number, you could also generate alerts or
block legitimate traffic destined for your
internal network. Content can help reduce
these false positives and permit
legitimate traffic by first inspecting the
payload. If it detects the specific
content, it would generate an alert or
block the traffic. The main difference
here is that to produce a match, the
packet needs specific content, not just to
be delivered over that particular port. So
when legitimate traffic is sent to our
snort server, it also inspects the content
of the payload and in this case determines
that traffic can pass without an alert or
other action. Content has a few different
types and numerous modifiers that make it
highly customizable to specific
situations. The main three methods of
detection. Using content at a high level.
Our content itself, which bases detection
on matching the payload to a specific
string of text. If you want to hide this
content match criteria, you can instead
provide a hash value and use the protected
content option, which will hash portions
of the packet and attempt to match against
your provided hash value. The last option,
Raw Bites accomplishes the same task is
content but instead matches on a string of
hex characters. Let's look at a couple of
examples. We'll be using the basic content
option in our demo. So here I'll show you
an example of protected content and rob
bites. The first example is a protected
content using a shot to 56 value of the
content we want to detect. The hashing
algorithm used is also specified using the
hash option. Another example of the same
rule, but instead using raw bites. Looks
like this. Here we have the specific bites
and hex between two pipes. If the string
three Alfa 29 is detected in the packet,
this rule generating alert in the upcoming
demo. We're going to use a similar rule to
detect specific traffic meant to exploit
the vulnerability, and we're gonna block that traffic to prevent its execution.