[Autogenerated] In this clip, we're going
to discuss non payload detection rule
options, focusing on five of the available
options to detect packet header values or
behavior The five options will cover in
this course. R T T l frag bits de size
flags and flow. Let's go over each of them
quickly before we look at some examples.
The first option T T. L, was originally
designed to detect trace route attempts by
focusing on the timeto live value of each
packet. It could be set to alert based on
T T l values, or ranges between zero and 2
55. Trace route works by sending UDP
packets with progressively increasing TCL
values, waiting for an ICMP time exceeded
message to indicate the next top
configuring TT L, with a low range can be
used to detect an alert on a Siris of
packets with slowly increasing time to
live the next option. Frag bits can check
the I P header to determine if
fragmentation or reserve bids are set. I p
Fragmentation is one method of bypassing
intrusion detection systems like snort,
and the capability is built into network
scanning tools like end map specifically
for this purpose we could use frag bits to
alert on this type of traffic so we can
begin tracking it to detect scans or
fragmentation attacks. The size is used
for the opposite task of detecting
abnormally large packets attacks.
Exploiting a programs inability to handle
large packets are also called buffer
overflows. The extra data sent in the
packet can contain code, which the
vulnerable machine runs to trigger an
exploit. Large ICMP packets can also be
used to attempt denial of service attacks.
Using decides with a specific bite range
can alert you to the possibility of these
types of attacks. Flags are used to check
for specific TCP flags. This option can be
used to detect unexpected TCP packets used
in scans or attacks. The exploit machines
have difficulty handling them. One example
is a Christmas tree attack and the
associate ID and map Xmas. Scan these set
multiple TCP flags and send the package to
the system to either cause a denial of
service or cause the machine to report
something back to end map that indicates
support. State Finally flow is used in
conjunction with a session pre processor
in version two or the Stream TCP module in
version three to track the state of a
connection. This allows you to write rules
that tracked specific traffic flow
directions using flow. You can configure
rules to apply to either clients or
servers within the same network, allowing
you to be more specific with the devices
you track within your home net. We'll use
a few of these in the next demo, but
before we start, let's look at an example
Rule using the flow option. This example
is a modification of the raw bite's
content rule we saw earlier to detect an
attempted back door of the vulnerable BSF
TPD service. The source network was
changed at home net so we can detect
internal attempts to open the same
________. We added the flow option to
detect traffic with content destined for
the FTP server. This rule will ignore
traffic from the FTP server to any client
that would match our content rules, since that would not indicate a ________ attempt